Guide to the Queer Straight Alliance Papers1977-2020
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Queer Straight Alliance records
1977-2020
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Queer Straight Alliance
2632
Collection 2632
0.7 linear feet
The Queer Straight Alliance provides a safe, friendly environment for the LGBTQ+ (Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and other identities) members, as well as creating political awareness, social activities, and informaation to the community of Montana State University. This collection includes correspondence and paperwork related to the founding and operations of Queer Straight Alliance on campus and issues that they were concerned with since 1977.
The Queer Straight Alliance at Montana State University (MSU) was founded in March 1977, by group president, Christopher Silberhorn. The student group was first organized under the name LAMBDA Gay Alliance. The Queer Straight Alliance provides a safe, friendly environment for the LGBTQ+ (Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and other identities) members, as well as creating political awareness, social activities, and informaation to the community of MSU. Other names the organization has been known by include Q-MSU and Gay Straight Alliance.
The larger national organization, LAMBDA Legal (LAMBDA Legal Defense and Education Fund), was founded by a group of volunteer lawyers when Attorney William J. Thom won a 1973 court case, gaining the right to found LAMBDA as a legal nonprofit organization in New York. By supporting efforts in impact litigation, societal education, and public policy reform, LAMBDA Legal stills works today to advance the civil rights of lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender communities as well as those with HIV/AIDS. LAMBDA Legal is responsible for winning several landmark cases such as Taylor vs. Rice in 2012 since their inception.
This collection includes correspondence and paperwork related to the founding and operations of Queer Straight Alliance on campus and issues that they were concerned with since 1977. Materials also include LGBQT resources, flyers, a scrapbook, a CD and audio tape, memos, newspaper articles, and other publications. A web archive begins in 2020.
This collection is open for research.
Correspondence, flyers, newspaper articles, memos, and paperwork created or collected by the Queer Straight Alliance of Bozeman, Montana was donated to Montana State University by the group on March 1, 2018.
Montana; Montana
Gay college students; Gay-straight alliances in schools; LGBT community centers; Transphobia; Homophobia; Gay culture; Gay liberation movement; Transgender college students; Transgender people in mass media; Gay press; Gay press publications; Lesbian college students; Lesbian community; Lesbians in mass media; Lesbians' writings; Bisexual college students; Bisexuals' writings; Two-spirit people; Asexual people; Asexual people's writings
Clubs and Societies; Colleges and Universities; Gays and Lesbians; Montana; Bozeman; Sound Recordings; Scrapbooks
Web archives; Scrapbooks; Newsletters; Newsletters; Newspaper clippings; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Clippings (Information artifacts)
- LAMBDA Magazines, 1986-2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A.I.D.S./H.I.V., 1986-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gay/Lesbian News, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  (letters, articles, etc.)
- LAMBDA: Resource People and Contacts, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Gay Health, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Newsletters and Articles Etc., 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  (Out-in-Montana, The Paper, and such)
- Murder, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  (includes film/photo negatives)
- Gay/Lesbian Harassment at MSU, 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  (Kecskes' articles)
- Laws, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  (Montana)
- Chronicle Articles off the Internet, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- LAMBDA Homophobia/Hate, 1987-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Publications, 1995-2003 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- QMSU Events/Movements, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- News – closet, petition, assault, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Positively Aware Subscription, 1999-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Flyers Q-MSU, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- News Around Country QMSU, 1997-2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Speakers That Contacted Us, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- QMSU Resources, 1985-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Club paperwork, 1999-2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- LAMBDA Events, 1987-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- LAMBDA speakers that contacted us, 1989-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- LAMBDA resources, 1990-1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- LAMBDA Alliance, 1977-2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- LAMBDA Alliance, 1984-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Lambda scrapbook, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2, Compact-disc 1, Audiocassette 1)
- Lesbian Connection and Memo, May-June 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Lesbian Connection, Volume 8, Issue 6, May/June 1986
- Human Rights Campaign, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Articles and Newsletters, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Students for Choice and Women's Center Writings, 1987-2016 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- QSA Awareness Materials, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Web Archive, 2020-2022